Kiss your nerves goodbye!
Evil Dead II is a horror, comedy, fantasy film directed by Sam Raimi.
Ash Williams and his girlfriend Linda find a log cabin in the woods with a voice recording from an archeologist who had recorded himself
reciting ancient chants from "The Book of the Dead." As they play the recording an evil power is unleashed taking over Linda's body.
Ash, played by Bruce Campbell.
Annie, played by Sarah Berry.
Jake, played by Dan Hicks.
Bobby Joe, played by Kassie DePaiva.
Possessed Henrietta, played by Ted Raimi.
Linda, played by Denise Bixler.
Evil Dead II (also known in publicity materials as Evil Dead 2: Dead by Dawn) is a 1987 American
comedy horror film directed by Sam Raimi, who co-wrote it with Scott Spiegel.
It is the sequel to The Evil Dead (1981) and the second
installment in the Evil Dead franchise.
It stars Bruce Campbell as Ash Williams, who vacations with
his girlfriend to a remote cabin in the woods.
He discovers an audio tape of recitations from a book of ancient texts, and when the
recording is played, it unleashes a number of demons which possess and torment him.
After the critical and commercial failure of Crimewave (1985), Raimi, producer Robert Tapert, and Campbell
began work on a sequel to The Evil Dead at the insistence of their publicist Irvin Shapiro.
Having endorsed the original film, author Stephen King brought the project to the attention of producer Dino
De Laurentiis, with whom he had been making his directorial debut Maximum Overdrive (1986).
De Laurentiis agreed to provide financial backing, and assigned the filmmakers a
considerably larger budget than they had worked with on the original film.
Although Raimi had devised a premise set in the Middle Ages and involving time travel,
De Laurentiis requested that the film be similar to its predecessor.
Evil Dead II was shot in Wadesboro, North Carolina and Detroit, Michigan in 1986, and featured extensive stop-motion animation and prosthetic makeup effects created
by a team of artists that included Mark Shostrom, Greg Nicotero, Robert Kurtzman and Tom Sullivan, the latter of whom returned from the original film.
The finished film was released in the United States on March 13, 1987; due to its high level of violence, it was released
through a pseudonymous distributor to curb an anticipated X rating from the Motion Picture Association of America.
Much like The Evil Dead, it was widely acclaimed by critics, who praised its humor, Raimi's direction, and Campbell's performance;
many have considered it superior to its predecessor and similarly as one of the greatest horror films ever made.
Despite being given a somewhat limited release, it was a minor box
office success, grossing just under $6 million.
As with the first film, Evil Dead II has accumulated a
large, international cult following.
In 1992, it was followed by the direct sequel Army of Darkness, which utilized Raimi's original premise; in 2013, it was followed by
the soft reboot and continuation Evil Dead; and in 2015, it was followed by the television series Ash vs Evil Dead.
A fifth film in the series, Evil Dead Rise, was released on April 21, 2023.
The film explores themes of deer, tape recorder,
chainsaw, spirit, cabin in the woods.
The tone is lighthearted and dark.